A racing second hand, a shooting comet,
،عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
a pop-up doll, and broken ceramic!
دمية آلية الخروج وخزف محطّم
Mystery-solving logic is helpful against people's dry hearts!
المنطق المفكّك للغموض مفيد في مواجهة القلوب الجافّة
Today is an exciting first errand! Exhilaration turns into terror!
!قضية اليوم إرساليّة أولى مثيرة! البهجة تنقلب لرعب
He sees the single truth for what it is--
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The First Errand Murder Case
جريمة قتل الإرسالية الأولى
Beika Shopping Street-- First Errand Competition
مسابقة الإرسالية الأولى لشارع تسوّق بيكا
I'm so glad it's sunny out!
هذا جميل، من الرائع أن الطقس صحو
Ugh.
يا إلهي
Good luck!
!بالتوفيق
Group #1 has just left Beika Park!
غادرت المجموعة الأولى حديقة بيكا للتوّ
What place will the Junior Detective Club's own Wataru-kun get?
أيّ مركز سيحققه واتارو-كن تحت أنظار فرقة فتيان التحرّي يا ترى؟
We're counting on you guys!
!بالتوفيق يا رفاق
Get good shots, Mitsuhiko!
صوّر جيّداً يا ميتسوهيكو
You too, Genta-kun!
!أنت أيضاً
Conan-kun! Don't get left behind!
!كونان-كن! لا تتأخّر
I won't!
أجل
Why do I have to do this too?
لمَ عليّ فعل هذا أيضاً؟
Kids'll be kids. Go get 'em.
يبقى الأطفال أطفالاً، انطلق
The shopping street has some of your biggest clients!
يحوي شارع التسوّق عدداً من أكبر عملائك
Hi, there!
!مرحباً
Why did we accept this job?!
لمَ قبلنا هذا العمل؟
Isn't it obvious?
أليس واضحاً؟
So the public will love us! We asked really hard for the job!
كي ننال حُب العامة! ألححنا عليهم أن يعطونا العمل
What? So we asked for the job?!
!ماذا؟ أي أننا من طلب؟
Got a problem with that, Conan?!
لديك مشكلة في ذلك يا كونان؟
Never heard of such a detective group...
...لم أسمع بفرقة تحرٍّ كهذه قبلاً
Wataru-kun has just passed the vegetable store! Oh no!
!عبر واتارو-كن محلّ الخضروات للتوّ! كلا
Now he can't buy a daikon! What will come of this?!
!لن يستطيع شراء دايكون هكذا ما الذي سيؤول له الأمر؟
The Junior Detective League was put in charge of recording the event.
كُلّفت فرقة فتيان التحرّي بتسجيل هذا الحدث
It would later be aired on local TV, and the children would get prizes
سيُبثّ لاحقاً على محطّة تلفازية محلّية ويحصل الأطفال على جوائز
depending on their rank.
بناءً على مراكزهم
The rules are simple. Go alone from Beika Park
القواعد بسيطة، اذهب بمفردك من حديقة بيكا
to Beika Shopping Street, some 500 meters away,
لشارع تسوّق بيكا الذي يبعد خمسمئة متر
buy the items on the shopping list, and return.
اشتر الأغراض في قائمة التسوّق وارجع
However, no parents or onlookers can talk to or help them--
لا يُسمح للآباء أو المتفرجين الكلام معهم أو مساعدتهم
they can only watch.
يمكنهم المراقبة وحسب
But it's actually tough.
لكنّ هذا شاق في الواقع
Some kids keep coming back to ask their mothers for help,
يرجع بعض الأطفال لطلب المساعدة من أمهاتهم
some kids get lost,
ويتوه بعضهم
some buy toys and candy for themselves,
وهناك من يشتري ألعاب وحلويات ويرمي قائمة الشراء
and some spend all their time in arcades.
ومن يقضي وقته في مركز الألعاب
Kids these days!
...يا إلهي، أطفال هذه الأيام
I can't watch this...
لا أستطيع المشاهدة
For sure...
فعلاً
You guys are kids too.
أنتم أطفال أيضاً
His group's up!
دور مجموعته الآن
That's Hiroshi-kun; he lives in my neighborhood!
إنّه يُدعى هيروشي-كن، يعيش في حيّنا
He hasn't started yet...
...لم يبدأ بعد
Alright! Let's get 'em!
!حسناً! لننل منهم
He's playing by himself?
يلعب بمفرده؟
What're you doing? Come on!
!ما الذي تفعله؟ أسرع
Hiroshi-kun's items are a toothbrush, fried tofu, and a shugi-bukuro.
أغراض هيروشي-كن هي فرشاة أسنان وتوفو مقلي وشوغي بوكورو
What's a shugi-bukuro?
ما هو الشوغي بوكورو؟
You got me.
بالفعل
Isn't it a bag for kings, bishops, and pawns?
أليس كيساً للملوك والفيل والبيادق؟
That's it!
!هذه هي
That's 'shogi'! (chess)
!تلك الشوغي
Geez! Maybe you should enter too! It'd be a good match!
!يا إلهي، ربما عليكم المشاركة ستكون مباراة جيّدة
There he goes!
!انطلق
Let's follow!
!لنلحق به
Where did he go?
أين ذهب هيروشي-كن؟
I don't see him anywhere...
لا أجده بأيّ مكان
He couldn't have gotten far.
لا يمكن أنّه ابتعد
This area is near your house, right?
هذه المنطقة بقرب منزلك، أليس كذلك؟
That's right.
صحيح
Which means that his house is also nearby.
مما يعني أنّ منزله بالقرب كذلك
Maybe he--
...أتقصد
went home?!
ربما عاد للمنزل؟
I didn't mean that. Hiroshi-kun is a loner, right?
ليس ذلك، هيروشي-كن طفل وحيد لأبويه، صحيح؟
Yes, but...
...أجل
So was I. I often played alone, just like him.
كذلك أنا، كنتُ ألعب بمفردي كثيراً مثله
In my own home, or nearby...
في منزلي، أو بالقرب
You did it!
!أنت الفاعل
Impressive!
!مُبهر
Ayumi-chan. Does he often play alone around here?
أيومي-تشان، أيلعب بمفرده في مكان قريب هنا عادةً؟
The empty lot! He's always playing there!
في الأرض الفارغة، يلعب بمفرده هناك دوماً
Let's check it out!
لنذهب لها
There he is!
!ذاك هو! هيروشي-كن
Hiiiya!
!أجل
Geez, not again!
يا إلهي، مُجدداً؟
He disappeared again...
...اختفى مرّةً أخرى
A bicycle track!
...أثر عجلة درّاجة
It's fresh, and suddenly gets deeper. It must've gotten heavier.
.إنّه حديث، كما يعمق بعد مسافة ربما أصبح أثقل
In other words, Hiroshi-kun got on the back of it...
ما يعني أنّ هيروشي-كن صعد على مؤخرتها
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Where are you going?!
أين تذهب؟
Wait for us!
!انتظرنا
Where to, Hiroshi-kun?
أين تريد الذهاب يا هيروشي-كن؟
Let me think...
...حسناً
Bye bye!
!مع السلامة
Bye!
مع السلامة
Hello!
!مرحباً
There he is!
!ها هو
It's him!
!هيروشي-كن
He waved and ran off...
...لوّح بيده ورحل
Is he playing a joke on us?
أيتلاعب بنا؟
I don't think so...
...لا أظنّه كذلك
An abandoned building? What was he doing here?
مبنى مهجور؟ ماذا كان يفعل هنا؟
Playing by himself again?
يلعب بمفرده مجدداً؟
He finally made it.
وصل أخيراً
He sure is troublesome.
إنّه مُتعب حقاً
He's finally at the shopping street! Will he be able to do his errands?
وصل شارع التسوق أخيراً! هل سيتمكن من إتمام إرساليته يا ترى؟
First is the toothbrush!
!فرشاة الأسنان أوّلاً
Oh no! He has to buy the toothbrush here!
!كلا! عليه شراء الفرشاة هنا
Maybe he's gonna get the fried tofu first?
ربما ينوي شراء التوفو المقلي أوّلاً
This is hopeless.
لا أمل في هذا
Oh, Hiroshi-kun...
...هيروشي-كن
What the... Someone cut this!
!هذا... أثر قطع بشفرة
What're you doing, Conan?! Let's go!
!ما الذي تفعله يا كونان؟! لنذهب
Right!
!أجل
A stationery shop?
قرطاسية؟
What's he buying here?
ماذا سيشتري هنا؟
One shugi-bukuro, please!
!شوغي بوكورو من فضلك
Sure thing!
حسناً، شوغي بوكورو
Here you are. That'll be 200 yen.
ها هو، الثمن 200 ين
That's a shugi-bukuro?!
!ذاك هو الشوغي بوكورو؟
Wow, Hiroshi-kun!
!مذهل يا هيروشي-كن
It was pure luck.
حظّ مُطلق
Only two left! What will he do?!
تبقى اثنان فحسب! ما الذي سيفعله؟
Here you are.
هاك
Thank you!
شكراً
Hiroshi-kun! Look out!
!هيروشي-كن! انتبه
Hey!
!انتبه
We won't make it!
!لن نصل في الوقت
Alright!
حسناً
Go!
!انطلقي
That was close...
...كان ذلك وشيكاً
No way! I put the side brake on!
!لا يمكن! رفعت المكبح الجانبيّ
That rope and this car! What's going on?!
سابقاً الحبل، والسيّارة الآن! ما الذي يجري؟
Where's Hiroshi-kun?
ماذا؟ أين هيروشي-كن؟
Oh, crap!
!كلا
Did we lose him again?!
هل فقدناه مجدداً؟
It's because you weren't filming!
!هذا لأنّك لم تكن تصوّر يا ميتسوهيكو
It's because you weren't!
!أنت أيضاً
What?!
!ماذا؟
Is someone out to get Hiroshi-kun?!
أيمكن أن أحدهم يستهدف هيروشي-كن؟
Hey! Conan!
!كونان
What is it?!
ما الخطب؟
This is Hiroshi's Yaiba figure!
!هذه دمية يايبا الخاصة بهيروشي
But where is he?!
لكن أين هو؟
He finally started his errands!
!بدأ تنفيذ إرساليته أخيراً
No!
كلا
He treasures this figure. It's weird for him to just leave it here.
،هذه لعبة هيروشي-كن الغالية من الغريب أن يتركها في مكان كهذا
Then where did he go?
أين ذهب إذاً؟
I don't know!
لا أدري
But he didn't go of his own accord! He was taken!
لكنه لم يذهب بإرادته، أخذه أحدهم
He was kidnapped!
!اختطفه من هنا
What?!
!ماذا؟
By who?!
!من؟
But they failed twice, so then--
...فشل مرّتين، ثمّ
That's bad!
!هـ-هـ-هذا سيّئ
Let's call the police!
!علينا الاتّصال بالشرطة
I'm not sure they'd believe us...
لا يقين بأنّ الشرطة ستصدقنا
What should we do then?
ماذا نفعل إذاً؟
First, let's find Hiroshi-kun!
!لنجد هيروشي-كن بأيّ حال
Then we can call the police! I hope I'm wrong, though...
.يمكننا الاتّصال بالشرطة بعدها ...آمل أنّي أبالغ بالتفكير
No luck!
لا جدوى
He's not that way, either!
لم نجده هناك أيضاً
Maybe we should go to the cops...
...ربما علينا مخاطبة الشرطة
Wait! If he is being targeted, then why?!
لحظة! إذا كان يُستهدف، فما سبب ذلك؟
Maybe that'll tell us where he is!
!ربما سيقودنا ذلك إلى مكانه
Genta. Mitsuhiko. Play back all your footage of Hiroshi-kun!
غينتا، ميتسوهيكو، أعيدا تشغيل تسجيل هيروشي-كن للآن
Did they tape something suspicious?
ماذا؟ أيوجد بالتسجيل شيء غريب؟
I didn't notice anything...
لم ألحظ شيئاً
Me neither...
ولا أنا
No! Go back a little!
!كلا! ارجعا أكثر
Go back more!
!أكثر، أكثر
Play that part again and pause it!
!أعيدا ذاك الجزء وأوقفاه
That's it!
!ها هو
Huh?
ماذا؟
What did you find?
ما الذي وجدته؟
Look closely. In Genta's camera, he looks like he's waving at us...
انظرا بإمعان، يبدو أنّ هيروشي-كن يلوّح لنا في كاميرا غينتا
...but in Mitsuhiko's camera--
...لكن في كاميرا ميتسوهيكو
What is this?
ما هذا؟
A curb mirror?
مرآة عبور؟
So Hiroshi-kun was waving at this?
كان هيروشي-كن يلوّح لها إذاً؟
Exactly.
أجل
More precisely, at a reflection of something in this mirror.
بشكل أدقّ، يلوّح لانعكاس ما عليها
The window!
!النافذة
Ah! Now I get it!
!هكذا إذاً! فهمت
He was waving to someone in that window!
!كان يلوّح لأحد في تلك النافذة
That's right. He didn't stop here to play.
صحيح، لم يأت هنا للهو فحسب
He had some kind of reason!
...كان لديه دافع! دافع ما
But what does that have to do with him being kidnapped?
لكن ما علاقة ذلك باختطافه؟
That's what we're checking.
هذا ما سنتحقق منه
Looks like I'm right!
يبدو أنّي أصبت
Hiroshi-kun's hat!
!قبعة هيروشي-كن
Does that mean he's inside?
أي أنّه في الداخل؟
Danger- Building Demolition
خطر هدم مبنى
The demolition is today! We don't have much time!
!موعد الهدم اليوم! لا وقت أمامنا
Alright! I'll go in alone...
...حسناً، سأدخل بمفردي و
Let's go, Junior Detective League!
!هيّا بنا، فرقة فتيان التحرّي
Careful-- the floor is fragile.
توخّوا الحذر، الأرض واهنة
Doesn't seem to be in here...
لا يبدو أنّه هنا
Let's check upstairs!
لنصعد الأدراج ونرى
No Entrance
الدخول ممنوع
We can't go any further.
لا يمكننا الصعود أكثر
That means nobody's upstairs.
هذا يعني أنّ لا أحد في الأعلى
We can go downstairs, though!
!يمكننا النزول
A basement?!
قبو؟
Do you think he's down here?
أتظنّونه هنا؟
Hiroshi-kun! Are you there?
هيروشي-كن! أأنت هنا؟
It's too dark to see anything...
...لا أرى شيئاً من الظلام
Hiroshi-kun!
!هيروشي-كن
A dead guy!
!جـ-جثّة
Is Hiroshi-kun dead too?!
!أيمكن أنّ هيروشي-كن ميت أيضاً؟
It's alright. He's alive.
لا تقلقوا، إنّه حيّ
An anesthetic!
!رائحة مخدّر
So he was kidnapped and brought here... by the killer!
!أي أنّه اُختطف وجلِب هنا... من قِبل القاتل
But what is a dead body doing here?
لكن لمَ توجد جثّة هنا؟
And why Hiroshi-kun?
ولمَ هيروشي-كن أيضاً؟
The killer planned to make the murder look like a demolition accident.
نوى القاتل جعل هذه الجريمة تبدو حادثة وقعت أثناء الهدم
The first floor was fragile; if any debris fell during the demolition,
كان الطابق الأوّل مُضعضعاً، إذا سقط أيّ حطام أثناء الهدم
the basement would be wrecked. That was the plan.
سيُسحق القبو، كانت تلك خطّته
But then Hiroshi-kun showed up.
لكنّ هيروشي-كن ظهر
Hello!
!مرحباً
Judging from his actions, I doubt he witnessed the actual murder.
أشك أنّه شهد الجريمة من سلوكه فيما بعد
But the killer didn't know how much he saw.
لكنّ القاتل لم يعرف كم رأى بالضبط
So they ran ahead to the shopping street--
...لذا سبقه لشارع التسوق و
--but failed.
لكنّه فشل
The killer eventually decided to fake his death too.
قرّر القاتل في النهاية جعله يموت هنا في ما يبدو حادثة هدم
That's right.
صحيح
You're pretty smart for a couple of kids.
أنتم أذكياء بالنسبة لأطفال
But this is the end.
لكن هذه النهاية
Oh no!
!كلا
He's going to kill us too!
!سيقتلنا أيضاً
No way!
!لا يُعقل
This can't be happening!
!مستحيل
No!
!لا
What's taking them so long?
تأخّر كونان-كن والبقية
Hiroshi-kun isn't back yet, either. What could they be doing?
لم يرجع هيروشي-كن بعد، ماذا حصل يا ترى؟
Probably loitering around somewhere. Kids'll be kids.
يعبثون في مكان غالباً، فيبقى الأطفال أطفالاً
Let's get this done quickly.
لننته من هذا سريعاً
No good. It won't budge.
لا جدوى، لا يتزحزح البتّة
I don't wanna die down here!
!كلا! لا أريد الموت هنا
Mommy!
!أمي
Ayumi-chan! Calm down!
!أيومي-تشان! اهدئي
This is all because you wouldn't call the police!
كلّ هذا لأنّك رفضت الاتّصال !بالشرطة يا كونان
But you're the one who wanted to come in here!
!لكنّك من أراد الدخول هنا
Yeah, but--
...أ-أجل، لكن
An earthquake?!
زلزال؟
No! The demolition's started!
!كلا، بدأ الهدم
It's all over!
!إنّها النهاية
It's hopeless!
!لا أمل
Mommy!
!أمّي
Running water? Could it be?
ماء جارٍ؟ معقول؟
We might survive, guys!
!قد ننجو يا رفاق
Stop worrying! They'll come back! Kids'll be kids!
!لا تقلقي، سيرجعون! فالأطفال يبقون أطفالاً
But what if something bad has happened to them?!
!لكن ماذا لو حلّ مكروه بهم؟
Let's look for them!
!لنبحث عنهم
Stop pulling so hard!
!لا تشدّي بهذه القوّة
What's that sound?
ما هذا الصوت؟
How did you...
...أنتم
Surprised?
تفاجأت؟
You shouldn't underestimate us!
!عليك ألّا تستهين بنا
We're the Junior Detective League!
!نحن فرقة فتيان التحرّي
Too bad, Mister.
للأسف يا سيّد
We should've been crushed along with that dead body,
كان يُفترض أن نُسحق مع الجثّة
but thanks to the weak support struts, the basement wall crumbled.
لكن انهار حائط القبو بسبب الدعائم الضعيفة
Luckily, it led right into an underground tunnel...
وصادف أنّه يقود لنفق تحت الأرض لحسن الحظ
Mister! You have another store, right?
أيّها السيّد، لديك متجر آخر، صحيح؟
That's great!
!حمداً لله
Fried tofu and one toothbrush, please!
توفو مقلي واحد وفرشاة أسنان من فضلك
What?
ماذا؟
What's going on?
ما الذي يجري؟
Oh! That was your convenience store, wasn't it?
صحيح! كان متجر تمويناتك هنا، أليس كذلك؟
That's right.
بلى
A dirty stockbroker tricked me, and I racked up more debt
خدعني سمسار محتال، وتراكمت ديوني
than I could ever pay off, and my family ran out on me.
بحيث لا أستطيع دفعها مهما عملت، وهربت عائلتي
It was that stockbroker that I killed.
من قتلتُه كان ذاك السمسار
My store was repossessed and shut down.
اُستولي على متجري بسبب الديون وأُغلق
It wasn't as popular as stores on the shopping street--
لم يكن يرتاده زبائن كثُر كالمتاجر في شارع التسوّق
it would be quickly forgotten.
كان ليُنسى سريعاً
But Hiroshi-kun remembered it!
!لكنّ هيروشي-كن تذكّره
He came to buy from your store for his first errand!
!أتى للشراء من متجرك في إرساليته الأولى
Hello!
!مرحباً
He did...
...هـ-هكذا إذاً
The very same Hiroshi-kun that you tried to kill...
وحاولتَ أنت قتله
I'm sorry, little boy! Forgive me!
!آ-آسف يا ولد! سامحني
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
What're you guys doing?!
ما الذي تفعلونه؟
A huge victory for the Junior Detective League!
!نصر كبير لفرقة فتيان التحرّي
Wow! That's what happened? Good job!
مُدهش، هذا ما حصل؟ أحسنتم العمل
I guess kids'll be kids. How boring.
يبقى الأطفال أطفالاً حقاً، مُمل تماماً
Guess I'll have a bath, some booze, and get some shut-eye!
سأرجع وأستحمّ وأغرق في الشراب
I was watching that apartment's veranda.
كنتُ أشاهد شرفة تلك الشقّة
This was a murder! Meaning the most suspicious person is--
...هذه جريمة قتل! ما يعني أنّ الأكثر شبهة
--the guy on the phone who told her not to jump.
هو هذا الشخص الذي حاول منعها من القفز على الهاتف
But how could he do it from so far away?!
لكن كيف استطاع فعلها من تلك المسافة؟
The Illustrator Murder Case
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
On the next Conan--
جريمة قتل الرسّامة التوضيحية
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Contact Lens Set.
مجموعة عدسات لاصقة
Next episode is a little grown up.
ندخل عالم البالغين قليلاً في الحلقة القادمة
Conan-kun, you're not allowed to see that.
!كلا! لا تنظر يا كونان-كن